now let's discuss the solution to our
dependencies in has--it's quiz first
let's figure out the dependencies again
dependencies are a property of the
program alone so we don't have to worry
about the pipeline yet each of these
instructions has a dependence on r1 from
the add to that instruction which of
these dependencies are hazards does
depend on the pipeline to check whether
the dependence is a hazard we need to
figure out when does the read of the
register happen and when does it get
written in the stage where the subtract
is reading the register the add is still
writing it so the subtract may not get
the value from the add so there is a
hazard here in the cycle when the divide
is reading the register r1 the subtract
is here and the add has left the
pipeline which means the divide is
reading the value of r1 that was already
written by the add so there is no hazard
here and of course the multiply reads
the same register one cycle after the
divide so it also has no hazard